Robert Huo

Mobile: 0450 950 778

E-mail: roberthuomelbourne@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/robert-da-huo/

My site: https://www.devhuo.com/

Summary

- Three years of practical experience in developing complex, high profile Commercial projects in Agile/Scrum team as a full stack developer.
- Specialized in JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, APIs and MongoDB to deliver testable, maintainable, and reusable code.
- A clear, concise, and effective team player in teamwork.
- Adaptable, self-motivated, enthusiastic developer with positive attitude and Great analytical and problem solving abilities, maintaining a high level of efficiency under high pressure.
- Practical knowledge of web development technologies, and always willing to learn and develop new technical skills.

Skills

Front-end: HTML5, CSS3, SASS/LESS, Bootstrap4, Flexbox, JavaScript(Vanilla,

ES6+), jQuery, Pug, Responsive Design, React.js(SPA), Redux.js, Redux-saga, Redux-thunk, DvaJS, Material-UI, Ant-design, Moment.js,

TypeScript, UmiJS, Styled-Component

Back-end: Node.js, Express.js, KeystoneJS, JWT, Helmet, Java, Python

API: RESTful API, GraphQL(Apollo), WebSocket API, Swagger, JSON, Ajax,

axios

Database: MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose

Tools: Visual Studio Code, Postman, Git, Github, BitBucket, JIRA, Trello, NPM,

Webpack, Babel, ESLint, WordPress, Jest, Enzyme, Zeplin

Cloud Services: AWS Route 53, AWS Amplify, Heroku

Methodologies: Agile/Scrum/Kanban, TDD

Experience

Full-stack developer

Nov 2019 – Current

JR Academy, Remote

- https://learn.jiangren.com.au
- https://jiangren.com.au
- Tech stack: HTML5, CSS3, Less, SASS, JavaScript(ES6 +), React, React-router, Redux, Redux-saga, UmiJs, DvaJs, Ant Design, Pug, Bootstrap, Node.js, KeystoneJS, Express, RESTful API, Swagger, MongoDB, Mongoose, momentjs, NPM, Git, BitBucket, JIRA, Postman, Zeplin, webpack, babel, eslint, prettier.
- Job purpose: Worked with an Agile team, implemented a server-side rendered company website and an online learning dashboard used by students and mentors based on MERN Stack(MongoDB, Express, ReactJS, Node.JS), HTML template engine Pug and Sass, used Git and Bitbucket for version control. Developed main

functions of official website and dashboard by following the BA's instructions. Responsible for the further performance improvement, function extensions and maintenance of existing web applications and technologies. Researched, collected, and reported information on the ability and capacity of company products, and refactor current codes to get a better performance.

- Frontend Tasks: Managed states by Redux-saga, built responsive webpages and scalable user interface based on the Zeplin UI design, managed data-flow using network, refactored existing code from commonJS to ES6, implemented main functions of dashboard including signing up for courses, checking assignments with attached materials left by teachers, listing students' submissions to the teacher and course link managements, adjusted webpack configurations to get a better performance.
- Backend Tasks: Designed RESTful APIs and implemented CRUD nodejs server, sent notification emails by using nodemailer, refactored existing code from commonJS to ES6, adjusted webpack configurations to get a better performance,, manipulated mongodb database by using mongoose.
- Bugfix: Fixed data flow and UI, managed LocalStorage to store correct data, fixed responsive pages, fixed and improved double sided data binding.

Web developer

May 2018 – Oct 2019

Kinly Beauty, Melbourne

- As a part-time developer, maintained and designed existing website to a responsive and user-friendly website, developed a brand new website by using Wordpress.
- Renewed company information and relevant materials.
- Fixed css styles to meet the design pattern requirements.
- Implemented simple SEO managements.

Software developer

Oct 2015 – Feb 2016

IBM China, Dalian China

- Written in Java, Javascript, HTML, CSS, the project was developed for Coco Cola and P&G.
- Made unit test and black box test.
- Worked in an Agile team, Organized and communicated team agenda, prepared test plan and cases.

Selected Projects

- Used current popular technologies, such as ReactJS(hooks, contexts etc), axios, GraphQL, typescript, Jest, AWS Route 53 and Amplify, implemented functions and performs testing and debugging of applications.
- Most of the projects are business projects or have business potential.

Weather App (https://weather-inquire.netlify.com/)

- A web application provides real time and forecast weather information fetched through OpenWeatherMap API, for the selected locations. Logging user favourite cities' weather updations.
- Has business project potential.
- Followed High cohesion & Low coupling principle to build a weather inquire APP including adding favourite cities function and single sign-on application by using ReactJS and Redux-thunk.

- Back-end written in Node.js(express), deployed on Heroku, frontend deployed on Netlify.
- Friendly designed UI, which could be reused easily.

Warhammer Player Community (https://warhammer-community.netlify.com/)

- Business project used for warhammer players social contact.
- Back-end implemented by Node.js(Express), deployed on Heroku, used nodemailer to send contact forms to back-end.
- Friendly designed UI, which could be reused easily, written in ReactJS, React Bootstrap, React-Router.

Pizza-Online-order (https://pizza-online-order.netlify.com/)

- Business project used for online pizza order.
- Implemented input validations including email format, email confirmation functions By using ReactJS.
- Back-end deployed on Heroku, which sends user's info and pizza info to chef through email.
- Simplified UI with input validators, which could keep users making valid input.

Personal Blog(https://www.devhuo.com/)

- A responsive personal website for showcasing portfolios with detailed information. Supports both English and Mandarin.
- Deploys on AWS(Amplify & Route 53).
- Implemented user-friendly responsive pages and mobile devices pages by ReactJS, React-Router, and Antd.
- Embraced current tech-trend such as hooks, Sass.
- Implemented language switched function.

Everwell Medical Center official website(http://everwellmedical.com.au/)

- Maintained and updated a commercial project using wordpress.
- Worked with project teams to determine an appropriate UI appearance and implemented by refactoring css styles, added new user profiles and managed media.
- Fixed css features on both PC and mobile.
- Used Php and MySQL as back-end.

Education

Master of Information Technology, University of Melbourne, AUSTRALIA Bachelor of Computer Science and Technology, Jilin University, CHINA

Referees

Available upon request